A Finding Aid to the Hughie Lee-Smith Papers, circa 1890-2007, bulk 1931-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.leeshugh
Archives of American Art
- Writings, circa 1934-1998; Series 3; 0.8 Linear feet Box 8-9
  - "Observations", circa 1960s-1972 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Personal History and Early Influences, circa 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - "Seven 19th-Century Afro-Amer. Artists", undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - "Special Problems of the Contemporary Afro-American Artist", 1969 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Speech to Association for Study of Negro Life History, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Speech at Unveiling Banquet, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Statement on Art, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Wayne State University Writings, circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Writings Portfolio, circa 1934 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Writings and Notes, circa 1936-1996 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Carol Ann Armstrong, "Hughie Lee-Smith", 1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Michael Brenson, "The Hughie Lee-Smith Moment", 1995 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Helen Bowers, Poetry, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Alice Carroll, Memorandum Book, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Mary Lynne Ehrbar, "Hughie Lee-Smith: Artist Between Reality and Fantasy", 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Zita Rahn Ferrell, Thesis Draft, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Ida Catherine Hawkins, "Hughie Lee-Smith", 1994 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Sherrie L. Howard, Articles for Emerge Magazine, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Kurt Mack, "Portrait of Hughie Lee-Smith: The Artistic Experience of an Afro-American", 1986 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Julia Natasha Renn, "Hughie Lee-Smith: 1915-", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Lowery Sims, "Hughie Lee-Smith: Romantic Realist or Alchemical Poet?", 1998 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Peter Stegall, Essay, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Carol Wald, Book Proposal, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Lin Yatta (Doris Turner), "Journeynotes", 1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by Others, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Personal Business Records, 1934-2001; Series 4; 1.6 Linear feet Box 9-11, 35
  Personal business records include documents on the sales and loans of Hughie Lee-Smith's artwork; scattered financial documents, such as bank records, receipts, tax documents, earnings statements, and lists of income and expenses; and contracts and agreements with various art galleries and other organizations. Also found are files regarding art commissions, participation in exhibition juries, and visiting artist positions. Additional material includes records of gifts of Lee-Smith's paintings to museums, lists of his works of art, and records of his employment at the Art Students League.
  Files are arranged alphabetically. Items within folders are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Address Books, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 20-24)
  - Apartment Lease Records, 1961-1978 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Art Juries, circa 1951-1996 (Box 9, Folder 26-27)
  - Automobile Records, circa 1952-1976 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Bank Records, 1940s-1980 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Commission, "Cityscape" for Sate of New Jersey, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 30-31)
  - Commission, David Dinkins Portrait, 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Commission, General Services Administration, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 33-34)
  - Commission, Mosaic "Idyllic Landscape", 1988 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Commission, Illustration for New Yorker, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Commission, "The Promise", 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Commission, Reginald Lewis Portrait, circa 1996-1997; Includes 3 videocassettes (VHS). (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Commissions Not Awarded, 1983; 1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Conference on the Functional Aspects of Black Art, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Consignments, Janet Nessler (Petite Galerie, Inc.), 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Contracts and Agreements, 1950s-1994 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Dan Dragan Photographic Services, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Donations to the Art Students League, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Donations to Printmaking Workshop, 1986-1997 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Donations to the Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Earnings Statements, 1952-1984 (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
  - Easels Brochure, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Employment Records, Art Students League, 1978-1989 (Box 10, Folder 15-16)
  - Employment Records, Howard University, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Evans-Tibbs Collection, 1983-1989; 1997 (Box 10, Folder 18-20)
  - Gift to Capitol Art Foundation, 1998; 2001 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Gift to Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Gift to Museum of International Art, Sofia, Bulgaria, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship Application, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Hiram Walker Awards Competition, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Income (Paintings), 1966-1975; 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Income and Expenses, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - International Review of African American Art (Hampton University), 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 28-29)
  - Lecture Tour of Three Episcopal Church Colleges, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Life Insurance, 1936-1975 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Lists of Artwork, circa 1950s-1970s; 1993 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Loan to Appleton Museum of Art, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - New Jersey State Museum, 1985-1987; 1990-1999 (Box 10, Folder 34-35)
  - Patron File, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Photographic Processing, 1998-2000 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Plans for 1947 Art Calendar, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Property and Rental Documents, 1972; 1958 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Receipts, 1934-1990s (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Rental Gallery of the Founders Society, Detroit Institute of Arts, 1976-1985; 1966 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Sales, circa 1943-1981 (Box 10, Folder 42-45)
  - Summer Art Program at Vermont Academy, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Tax Documents, 1943-1979 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Television Demonstration, "The Thirteen Collection", 1979 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Tuition Receipts, 1936-1959 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Visions Foundation Symposium, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 50-51)
  - Visiting Artist, Vermont Studio Center, 1995-1997 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Works Progress Administration in Ohio, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Oversized, Commission, David Dinkins Portrait, 1993-1995 (Box 35)
    Oversized material from Box 9, Folder 32.
- Exhibition Files, circa 1973-2001; Series 5; 1.2 Linear feet Box 11-12
  Exhibition files document select exhibitions in which Hughie Lee-Smith participated, primarily during the 1980s and 1990s. Files may include correspondence, loan agreements and planning documents, checklists, catalogs, press clippings, and photographs. Researchers should note that the files here do not represent all of Lee-Smith's exhibitions and additional documentation may be included in Series 2: Correspondence.
  Files are arranged in chronological order by date of exhibition.
  - Grand Central Galleries - "Lee-Smith: Paintings and Drawings" (1973), circa 1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Detroit Historical Museum - "Historical Roots: The Black Artist in Michigan" (1980) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - YM/YWHA - "New Jersey Artists of the National Academy of Design" (1983) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - CRT's Craftery Gallery - "Hughie Lee-Smith: A Collection of Drawings and Paintings" (1984), 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Malcolm Brown Gallery - "Hughie Lee-Smith Paintings" (1984), 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The Art Center, Battle Creek - "The Metaphysical Art of Hughie Lee-Smith" (1986), 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - The West Collection - "Art and the Law" (1986), 1985-1991 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Kenkeleba Gallery - "Unbroken Circle: Exhibition of Afro-American Artists of the 1930's and 1940's" (1986) (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Hudson Guild, Various Exhibitions (1986-1988) (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Jamaica Arts Center - "Masters and Pupils" (1987), 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Isobel Neal Gallery Ltd. - "Hughie Lee-Smith and John Rozelle" (1987) (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Kenkeleba Gallery - "Three Masters: Eldzier Cortor, Hughie Lee-Smith, Archibald John Motley" (1988), 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Montclair State College - "Joining Forces: Hughie Lee-Smith and John W. Rhoden" (1988), 1982-1990 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Malcolm Brown Gallery - "Hughie Lee-Smith" (1988), 1988-1993 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - New Jersey State Museum - "Hughie Lee-Smith Retrospective Exhibition" (1988-1989), 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
  - The Studio Museum in Harlem - "Hughie Lee-Smith: Retrospective Exhibition" (1989) (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Chicago Public Library - "Hughie Lee-Smith: Retrospective Exhibition" (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 21-22)
  - Artworks - "Twenty Five Years of Teaching Art" (1989), 1992 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute - "Hughie Lee-Smith: Paintings" (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Butler Institute of American Art - "Hughie Lee-Smith: Retrospective Exhibition" (1989) (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Lehman College - "Black Printmakers and the WPA" (1989) (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Printmaking Council of New Jersey - "New Jersey Print Masters" (1991) (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Gallery at Bristol-Myers Squibb - "The Expanding Circle: A Selection of African American Art" (1992), 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Newark Museum - "Alone in a Crowd" (1992), 1992-1997 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Mailou Art Fest - "Living Legends" (1992), 1995 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - New Jersey Center for Visual Arts - "Clarence Holbrook Carter and Hughie Lee-Smith: Two Master Painters" (1992) (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Flushing Town Hall - "Hughie Lee-Smith: Magic Realist Paintings" (1993) (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - National Museum of American Art - "Free Within Ourselves: African-American Artists in the Collection of the National Museum of American Art" (1994-1995) (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Long Beach Museum of Art - "Exultations" (1995) (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Gallery at Bristol-Myers Squibb - "Hughie Lee-Smith: An Overview" (1995), 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 35-36)
  - Rockland Community College - "African-American Printmaking" (1995) (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Cleveland Museum of Art - "Transformations in Cleveland Art 1796-1949" (1996), 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Cleveland Artists Foundation - "Yet We Still Rise" (1996), 1995-1998 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Malcolm Brown Gallery - "Hughie Lee-Smith: Cleveland Visionary" (1996), 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Winston Salem Delta Fine Arts, Inc. - "...of time and space, paintings by Hughie Lee-Smith" (1997), 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 41-42)
  - Ogunquit Museum of American Art - "Hughie Lee-Smith: A Retrospective" (1997), 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Appleton Museum of Art - "Hughie Lee-Smith: A Retrospective" (1998), 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - University of New Mexico - "Stages of Influence: The Universal Theater of Hughie Lee-Smith" (2001), 1999-2001 (Box 12, Folder 5-7)
- Organization Records, 1941-2005; Series 6; 2.1 Linear feet Box 12-14
  This series includes files maintained by Hughie Lee-Smith for organizations in which he participated. Of note are his participation as a member of the National Academy of Design and Century Association, as vice-president of the Ira Aldridge Society, and as president of the Audubon Artists. Files may include correspondence, reports, planning documents, agendas, meeting minutes, event materials, publications, and photographs.
  Files are arranged alphabetically by organizations. Documents for each organization are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1987-1996; 1961 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - American Society of African Culture, 1960-1962 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Artists' Fellowship, Inc., 1980-1999 (Box 12, Folder 10-16)
  - Artists League of the Midwest, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Art Students League, 1988-2005 (Box 12, Folder 18-19)
  - Audubon Artists, Inc., 1974-1995 (Box 12, Folder 20-25)
  - Century Association of New York, 1982-1999 (Box 12, Folder 26-31)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Inc., 1986-1998 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Ford Local #600, 1947; 1941 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Ira Aldridge Society, 1960-1970 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Lotos Club, 1984-1999 (Box 13, Folder 3-11)
  - National Academy of Design, 1966-1998 (Box 13, Folder 12-28)
  - National Academy of Design, 1995-1998 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - New Jersey State Council on the Arts, 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - New York Artists Equity Association, 1981-1991; 1961 (Box 14, Folder 4-6)
  - Princeton Art Association, 1963-1987 (Box 14, Folder 7-10)
  - Studio Museum in Harlem, 1980-1988 (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
- Printed Material, 1919; 1930-2007; Series 7; 8.5 Linear feet Box 14-22, 34
  Printed material consists primarily of exhibition announcements and invitations for exhibitions of Lee-Smith's work and the work of others. Also found are journals, newsletters, magazines and other publications from various art organizations and schools, as well as conference programs, press releases, and news clippings mostly related to Lee-Smith's professional activities. Additionally there are "source images" from various publications compiled by Lee-Smith for his artwork and a file of publications and clippings that were found on his office bulletin board at the time of his death.
  Files are arranged alphabetically by type of printed material.
  - Annual Report, Howard University, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Art Supply Catalogs and Brochures, 1998-2001 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1995-1996; 1999 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Book, American Visions: Afro-American Art 1986 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Book, Cities (Holt's Impact Series), 1968 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Book, I Live in Music, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Book, The Kennedy Years and the Negro, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Book, The State of Black America 1989 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Books on Art, 1947-1958 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Books of Poetry, 1943-1987 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Brochures, 1960s-1990s (Box 14, Folder 23-24)
  - Directories, Art Dealers Association of America, 1990; 1996 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Ecumenical Bulletins, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1940s-2000s (Box 14, Folder 27-29)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1940s-2000s (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Allied American Artists, 1958-1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Audubon Artists, 1962-1998 (Box 15, Folder 7-13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: National Academy of Design, 1964-1988 (Box 15, Folder 14-17)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: National Academy of Design, 1989-1998 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1940s-1979 (Box 16, Folder 3-18)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1980-1999 (Box 17, Folder 1-17)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, undated; 1998-2007 (Box 18, Folder 1-7)
  - Gallery Guides, 1983-1998 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Inspirational Clippings, 1970s-1990s (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Journal: LINEA (Art Students League), 1997-2000 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Magazines: International Review of African American Art, 1997-2001 (Box 18, Folder 11-13)
  - Magazines: Link (Cleveland Institute of Art), 1968-1999 (Box 18, Folder 14-16)
  - Magazines, 1930-1960s (Box 18, Folder 17-21)
  - Magazines, 1960s-1990s (Box 19, Folder 1-15)
    Oversized material housed in Box 34.
  - Magazines, 1990s-2004 (Box 20, Folder 1-5)
  - News Clippings, 1930s-1964; 1919 (Box 20, Folder 6-30)
  - News Clippings, 1963-2007 (Box 21, Folder 1-30)
  - Newsletters: Art Students League News, 1968-1995 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Newsletters: The Maryland Pendulum, 1980-1984 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Newsletters, 1939-2000 (Box 21, Folder 33-34)
  - Press Releases, 1959-1998 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Printed Material Regarding John Watson, 1996; 1985-1986 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Programs, 1930s-1990s (Box 21, Folder 37-39)
  - School Course Catalogs, 1977-1982; 1994-1998 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - School Publications, 1930s-1970s (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
  - Sheet Music, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Source Images for Artwork, 1950s-1990s (Box 22, Folder 6-14)
  - Things from Bulletin Board over Hughie's Desk, circa 1997-1999 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Travel Brochures, 1990s (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Year Book: Grand Central Art Galleries, Inc., 1968-1970 (Box 22, Folder 17-18)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1930s-2001 (Box 22, Folder 19-22)
  - Oversized Magazines, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 34)
    Oversized material from Box 19, Folders 1-15.
  - Oversized Printed Material, 1940s-2001 (Box 34)
    Oversized material from Box 22, Folders 19-22.
- Scrapbooks, circa 1938-1990s; Series 8; 0.2 Linear feet Box 22, 35
  Scrapbooks include loose scrapbook pages primarily containing news clippings about Hughie Lee-Smith and one scrapbook containing exhibition announcements. Exhibition announcements are for solo and group exhibitions of Lee-Smith's work. Researchers should note that many of these exhibition announcements are also found within Series 7: Printed Material.
  - Scrapbook Pages, circa 1938-1940s (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Oversized Scrapbook of Exhibition Announcements, 1940s-1990s (Box 35)
- Photographs, circa 1890-2003; Series 9; 4.4 Linear feet Box 22-26, 35, OV 37
  Photographs include many portraits of Hughie Lee-Smith, Lee-Smith in his studio, at events, and with friends and family. Also found are many family photographs, photographs of fellow artist Rex Goreleigh, and portraits of others possibly used as models for paintings. Additionally there are many photographs, slides, and transparencies of Lee-Smith's artwork, and a few photographs of exhibition installations.
  The bulk of this series consists of personal photographs and snapshots of Lee-Smith, Smith family, friends, events, exhibitions, and travels. Five photograph albums also include many photographs from the same events.
  Photographs are arranged by subject. Portraits of Hughie Lee-Smith and personal photographs are arranged in rough chronological order. Photographs included in the "Snapshots" folders were organized and inventoried by family before donation to the archives and the original order has been maintained.
  - Portraits of Hughie Lee-Smith, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 22, Folder 24-28)
    Oversized material housed in Box 35 and OV 37.
  - Photographs of Hughie Lee-Smith Teaching at Vermont Academy, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Photographs of Hughie Lee-Smith at Exhibition Openings, circa 1950s-1990s (Box 22, Folder 30-31)
  - Photographs of Hughie Lee-Smith at Various Events, 1951-1995 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Hughie Lee-Smith Painting a Commissioned Portrait, 1950s (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Early Family Photographs, circa 1890s-1930s (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Oversized items housed in Box 35.
  - Family Photographs, early 1900s-1920s (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Personal Photographs, 1930s-1990s (Box 23, Folder 5-17)
  - Partial Inventory of Snapshots, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Snapshots, 1920s-1999 (Box 23, Folder 19-32)
  - Snapshots, 1920s-1999 (Box 24, Folder 1-17)
  - Snapshots - Last Roll Taken by Hughie Lee-Smith, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Photographs of Catherine Ondine, circa 1990s (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Reginald Lewis, circa 1980s (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Photographs of Rex Goreleigh, circa 1965-1977 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Photographs of Samuel Gravely, 1970s (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Photographs of Friends from Navy, 1940s (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Portraits of Others, circa 1950s-1990s (Box 24, Folder 24-25)
  - Photographs of Exhibition Installation, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of Ford Local 600, UAW-CIO, circa 1951 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Photographs of Artwork, 1970s-1990s (Box 24, Folder 28-34)
  - Photographs of Artwork, 1970s-1990s (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
  - Photographs of Artwork (Altered Digital Prints), undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Photograph Album (Dismantled), 1930s-1977 (Box 25, Folder 5-11)
  - Photograph Album, 1960s-1991 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Photograph Album, 1990-1994 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Photograph Album of Events (Dismantled), 1974-1989 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Photograph Album of Exhibitions, 1995-1997 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Photograph Album of Oil Paintings, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Negatives, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 17-18)
  - Transparencies, circa 2000 (Box 25, Folder 19-20)
  - Slides - Sold Works, 1980s-1990s (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Slides - Retrospective Exhibition at New Jersey State Museum, circa 1988-1989 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Slides - Destroyed Works, 1980s (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Slides - Miscellaneous, 1970s-1990s (Box 26, Folder 4-9)
  - Lecture Slides - Renaissance, 1960s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Lecture Slides - 19th and 20th Century, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Lecture Slides - Miscellaneous, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Portraits of Hughie Lee-Smith, circa 1950s (Box 35)
    Oversized material from Box 22, Folders 25-29.
  - Oversized Early Family Photographs, circa 1900 (Box 35)
    Oversized material from Box 23, Folder 3.
  - Oversized Portraits of Others, circa 1950s (Box 35)
    Oversized material from Box 24, Folders 24-25.
  - Oversized Photographs of Artwork, 1970s-1990s (Box 35)
    Oversized material from Box 25, Folders 1-3.
  - Oversized Photograph Album of Exhibitions, 1995-1997 (Box 35)
    Oversized material from Box 25, Folder 15.
  - Oversized Portraits of Hughie Lee-Smith, 1954; 1990s (Box OV 37)
  - Oversized Photographs of Hughie Lee Smith at Various Events, 1974 (Box OV 37)
    Oversized material from Box 23, Folder 1.
  - Oversized Portraits of Others, 1980s (Box OV 37)
- Artwork, circa 1940s-1980s; Series 10; 0.2 Linear feet Box 26
  The small amount of artwork found here includes one Christmas card designed by Lee-Smith, his drawings of children around a maypole, a design entitled "Evolution of an Idea," and a few of his figure sketches. Also found are two sketchbooks belonging to Patricia Lee-Smith and a print by another unidentified artist.
  - Christmas Card by Hughie Lee-Smith, undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Drawings of Children and Maypole, undated (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - "Evolution of an Idea" Drawings, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Sketchbook, Patricia Lee-Smith, 1970s (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Sketchbook, Patricia Lee-Smith, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Sketches of Possible Home to Be Built, circa 1964 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Sketches, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified Print, undated (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Unused Dry-point Etching Plate, circa 1940s (Box 26, Folder 21)
- Interviews, 1973-1998; Series 11; 2.1 Linear feet Box 26-28
  Found here are numerous interviews of Hughie Lee-Smith. Included are formal interviews; informal discussions between Lee-Smith, his wife Patricia, family, and friends at his home; as well as recorded panel discussions and event speeches. Almost all interviews have been transcribed by his sister-in-law, Mary Jane Garrow. Recordings are on 33 sound cassettes, 1 sound tape reel, and four videocassettes.
  Most of the interviews were arranged and numbered by the transcriber in rough chronological order. This order has been maintained, followed by the untranscribed interviews and videocassette recordings.
  - Hughie Talks about his Opening at Malcolm Brown Gallery, 1984 October; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 26, Folder 22-23)
  - Panel Discussion, Art Institute of Chicago, 1985 September 7; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 26, Folder 24-25)
  - Lecture, "Art Goes to School", 1986 October 6; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Panel Discussion, "The Life and Times of Afro-American Art", 1987; 2 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
  - Interview with Maia Wechsler, 1988 October 31; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 27, Folder 5-6)